<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <Title><![CDATA[Let cheap fuel return, after a quarter century's absence]]></Title>
  <Date><![CDATA[2017-05-08T00:00:00Z]]></Date>
  <Source><![CDATA[Sing Tao Daily (Hong Kong)]]></Source>
  <Language><![CDATA[Chinese, Traditional]]></Language>
  <Body><![CDATA[The Competition Commission released the results of its auto fuel market study, pointing out that there is no evidence of price fixing among the oil firms or prices "rising fast but falling slowly", inevitably disappointing citizens hoping for the commission to "fight big tigers". However, it at least proposed some ways of enhancing competition or reducing the burden of car owners based on local conditions including the re-introduction of fuel with lower Research Octane Number (RON), which the government should take note and implement.
Under close monitoring by the Consumer Council, local oil firms have exercised restraint in "rising fast but falling slowly" when making retail adjustments according to supply prices. But retail oil prices are still higher than those in the USA, Europe and many Asian countries. The commission carried out a market study but as it was not a formal investigation, so it was limited in power to secure data from oil firms and could not find any evidence of collusion among them.
Hard to find collusion evidence among oil firms
In fact, firms controlling the local auto fuel market are mostly giant international enterprises with global businesses, so they have much experience in dealing with foreign competition laws. They also have many talents to ensure their companies are abiding by the law. Some even instruct their staff to avoid contact with "competitors" at social functions and to leave in high profile when they know about their presence to fend off suspicion. Under such strict demand, even if the commission launches a formal investigation, it may not necessarily find evidence of price fixing.
The fuel retail prices of several local firms move virtually in step. One of the reasons is that they are affected by supply prices of their major sources - oil refineries in Singapore. The second reason is that oil firms provide a variety of retail discounts making it hard for consumers to compare prices. As a result, prices change but consumers continue with their patronage. Seeing counterparts hiking prices with business unaffected, others follow suit for bigger profits. That has become a tacit understanding in the industry after so many years. There is no need for conspiracy.
Such "concerted action" even led to the disappearance of 95 RON fuel in less than half a year between 1991 and 1992. To lower pollution from auto emissions, the Environmental Protection Department required a minimum of 95 RON. But only fuel with 98 or above RON is available. Based on the experience in Singapore, 98 RON fuel is 15 per cent more expensive. In other words, Hong Kong's consumers have been forced to use "expensive fuel" for a quarter century.
Must break supply monopoly in the long term
The government has for many years tried to introduce competition in the auto fuel retail market with poor results mainly because the entry threshold is high, especially in land. Those unable to build their own oil depots and piers can only depend on existing big enterprises, which inevitably weakens competitiveness. The report proposes setting up a central oil depot by the government or a third party for lease to oil firms and a pipeline connecting with Shenzhen to reduce reliance on supply from Singapore. They are worth looking into but it is complicated and cannot be realized in the near future.
What will instantly be effective is to require in the new contracts that operators must provide 95 RON fuel as the contracts of 28 petrol stations expire next year. Such fuel is popular in many countries. The commission cited an earlier study, pointing out that over 99 per cent of vehicles in Hong Kong can use the fuel. Experts said that there is no special difference in performance compared with 98 RON fuel. Consumers should not be deprived of this cheap alternative by oil firms.
翻譯自五月五日《星島日報》社論
（http://std.stheadline.com/）
Vocabulary
restraint (n) —— 克制
collusion (n) —— 共謀
virtually (adv) —— 差不多
patronage (n) —— 光顧
conspiracy (n) —— 陰謀
depot (n) —— 倉庫
pipeline (n) —— 輸油管
alternative (n) —— 選擇
Useful Terms
price fixing —— 價格壟斷
social function —— 社交場合
oil refinery —— 煉油廠
entry threshold —— 入場門檻
Did you know
The Competition Commission is urging government officials and oil companies to address unusual practices in Hong Kong's auto fuel market, which it believes have contributed to high prices in the SAR despite falling prices globally. The transport industry in the past accused oil companies of price fixing, with drivers observing that pump prices at gas stations owned by different oil companies to often be the same. Commission senior executive director Rasul Butt, said that petrol in Hong Kong is priced "in parallel" by oil companies who are driven by similar operation costs.
1. The word _____ in the second paragraph is the opposite of "casual".
2. The government should consider the re-introduction of fuel with _____ Research Octane Number.
3. In the passage, the word _____ means "starts".
4. The government can help oil firms that are unable to build their own oil depots and _____.
5. According to the last paragraph, consumers should be allowed to use _____ RON fuel.
]]></Body>
</document>
